NICK PENDERGRAST

E. n.pendergrast@gmail.com — M. 022 6799738 — Auckland

SUMMARY

As a reliable and motivated team-player, with excellent communication skills, I always apply myself to workplace roles to the best of my abilities. I have spent the last 10 years in the beverage logistics industry in operations, supply chain coordination and team management positions. I am now looking to transition to a career in information technology. Since leaving the logistics field I have been engaged in self directed online study. The topics I am currently covering are SQL, Python, HTML, CSS and Javascript.

I would like to find a role where I can quickly expand my knowledge and increase my skill set. I enjoy a challenge, and prefer workplaces with a supportive team environment.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

JF HILLEBRAND NZ — Ponsonby — 2018 to July 2019

(Global beverage freight forwarder)

Position: Supply Chain Relationship Coordinator

In this role I am responsible for liaising with the SCM customers, suppliers, and JFH operations staff to ensure the specific requirements of the wine supply chain are met, which includes adequate supplier stock coverage, forecast communication, and in-time delivery.

JF HILLEBRAND I.T. B.V. — Haarlem, Netherlands — 2017 to 2018

(Global I.T. Office)

Position: Product Owner (FLOW logistics software)

During a 1 year secondment to the Hillebrand I.T. office, in Holland, I acted as product owner for the core in-house logistics application used by all freight offices of the JF Hillebrand global network. I was responsible for prioritising and communicating the requirements of the business to a software development team, and then communicating improvements and fixes back to the organisation. In this role I was exposed to the Agile development methodology, as well as the challenges and benefits that come from working within another culture.

JF HILLEBRAND NZ — Ponsonby — 2009 to 2017

(Global beverage freight forwarder)

Positions: export operator, import operator, team leader

During my time at JF Hillebrand I held a number of different roles, including export operator, import operator and team leader. My duties included:

- Analysing financial files
- Training new team members in the use of customs and in-house logistics application
- Liaising with customers, and our overseas offices, to resolve issues quickly
- Implementing new procedures to enhance efficiency
- Entering and submitting import and export customs entries (via Cargowise application)
- Ensuring team KPIs were met
- Leading the staff within my export team
- Reporting regularly to senior management

AGILITY LOGISTICS — Airport Oaks — 2008 to 2009

(Freight forwarding/general logistics)

Position: export operator/customer service

EDUCATION

Bachelor of Arts in Political Science
UNIVERSITY OF CANTERBURY — Riccarton, Christchurch 8041

Additional papers: level 1 computer science, linguistics, English literature, Roman history, management science, economics